

67 Olympic Pl, London, 🏫 Ontario, Canada – N6G 3P8

+1-(647)-470-3597

varughese.juby@gmail.com





PROFILE

I am a Junior Software Engineer with more than a year of Front-End and Full Stack experience on an Agile web application product development team using Go, Python, Django rest Framework, SQL Databases (MySQL, PostgreSQL), CSS (LESS and SASS), JavaScript (React.js, Redux and TypeScript), Jest, Webpack, Firebase, Google Analytics, Static Site Generator (Hugo), Linux and Digital Ocean.



EDUCATION

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT AND TECHNOLOGY ENTREPRENEURSHIP **DIPLOMA, LONDON LANGUAGE INSTITUTE (2019 - 2021)**

- Full Stack Development with Python, Go and React and TypeScript
- Digital Marketing by utilizing technologies like Google Analytics, Canva, Google Ads, Google Keyword Planner, SEO and Stukent platform.
- Entrepreneurship development with wireframing, prototyping, and client-based interactions with a high focus on fostering client relationships.

ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

B.ENG, MAHATMA GANDHI UNIVERSITY (2013 - 2017)

Advanced Production with Data acquisition systems (SCADA), CAD, C++, PCB and sensor design



WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | BCI INNOVATION LABS

LONDON, ONTARIO

MAY 2020 - CURRENT

- Increased metrics by developing multiple WordPress sites with custom integrations (MailChimp, Single Sign-on with all social media platforms, Google Analytics, etc.)
- Lead a team of developers for building an online platform that helps global talents to bring over to Canada.
- Effectively collaborated with stakeholders and developers to ensure quality products before the deadline.

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER | MIKA SOFTWARE CORPORATION

LONDON, ONTARIO

APRIL 2020 - JULY 2021

- Developed Frontend platforms on React.js from pure HTML and CSS
- Efficient Quality Assurance inspections on both Frontend and Backend to ensure errorfree applications.
- Assisted Senior Frontend Developers and Backend Developers with multiple tasks
- Effectively communicated with native and remote developers which helps in working collaboratively.
- Developed Hugo site with eCommerce integration that generated revenue for an international client.
- Wrote documentation using markdown programming language to save time with document styling.



SIDE PROJECTS

PRODUCT - BIODB

I have developed a prototype API platform for statistics computing, graphical generations and backup health kit data records that utilizes ETL database functions on Apple Health kit data (iPhone and iWatch) which allows the users to save their records in the database. I used Python and Django rest framework for the backend for controlling the data and created the GUI using React.js, Bootstrap and CSS3.

PRODUCT - PILLSHARE

I have developed a medical webapp that was built on React, TypeScript, Golang and Firebase, which tracks the vitals and pills intake of users and the data could be shared with family anywhere around the world. This platform primarily focusses on aging population which fosters their needs when it comes to their health tracking.



INTERESTS

My passions are Developer Meetups, Volleyball, and exploring the outdoors. I've been to 7 national parks to date.